<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>@Jordan Crane’s Blog - Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.jordancrane.me/https://blog.jordancrane.me/</link>
    <description>All entries in Blog on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 17:22:39 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.jordancrane.me/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Migrating from ProtonMail to Mailbox.org</title>
        <link>https://blog.jordancrane.me/posts/2020/12/migrating-protonmail-to-mailbox-org/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 17:22:39 -0800</pubDate>
        <author>Jordan Crane</author>
        <guid>https://blog.jordancrane.me/posts/2020/12/migrating-protonmail-to-mailbox-org/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years back I decided to switch from using a free email provider to a paid provider. This decision was driven by several factors, but the primary reasons were privacy concerns, and a desire for an email address with my domain name. I spent some time comparing different email providers, and settled on ProtonMail because they offered encryption at rest without any effort on my part, and they had a nicer iOS app than similar encrypted email providers. Now after several years of using ProtonMail, I am revisiting that decision. My motivations for doing so are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-reasons&#34;&gt;The Reasons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary motivation for my decision to migrate was surprisingly trivial&amp;mdash;a prime example of how a small annoyance, repeated many times, becomes a large annoyance. The ProtonMail iOS app, while nice, has one bug that drives me absolutely bonkers: you cannot import .ics files from the app into the iOS calendar. This means that anytime I would receive an invite to an event over email, I&amp;rsquo;d have to either forward the email to my iCloud email address and import the event to my calendar from another mail app, or open the email on my computer to add it to my calendar (the horrors!). On the surface this seems relatively inconsequential, but as someone who is chronically forgetful of things that I don&amp;rsquo;t write down, I found it to be a major hurdle to getting appointments and the like out of my inbox and into my calendar. Just that one extra step had a way of causing things to sit in my inbox and create additional mental clutter. Even more concerning was the fact that this issue has been brought to the attention of the ProtonMail team multiple times over the years and has still not been solved (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/ProtonMail/comments/cnm7pn/cannot_add_ics_file_as_calendar_entry/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3&#34;&gt;this Reddit post&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/ProtonMail/comments/jcbh9x/no_way_to_add_a_calendar_invite_from_email/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3&#34;&gt;another Reddit post&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/ProtonMail/comments/dikmxz/ios_ics_invites_not_updated_in_calendar/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3&#34;&gt;one more Reddit post&lt;/a&gt;). Perhaps most concerning to me was the last post, in which they implied the &amp;ldquo;solution&amp;rdquo; was to subscribe to yet another ProtonMail service (ProtonCalendar). That sort of response made me feel like ProtonMail was more interested in getting me fully invested in their ecosystem than they were in making their product work properly as a standalone offering, which I found hugely unappealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second biggest reason considering an alternative provider was that the &amp;ldquo;Plus&amp;rdquo; tier of ProtonMail&amp;rsquo;s offering doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer a catch-all address. Maybe this was just a case of me not understanding how expensive this is to manage, but it seems that almost every other email provider&amp;rsquo;s entry-level paid tier has this feature. ProtonMail&amp;rsquo;s entry-level tier is far from cheap ($4.50/month billed yearly), and I didn&amp;rsquo;t need any other features from their &amp;ldquo;Professional&amp;rdquo; tier, so it felt like a big jump to pay another $2/month just for that feature. For a comparison, Mailbox.org (the main alternative I was considering) offers a catch-all address for €1/month. Admittedly their offering is less security-focused, but a ~$3/month premium for said security seems a bit steep for not even offering feature-parity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I decided that Mailbox.org would be a suitable substitution. For secure communications I generally turn to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.signal.org/&#34;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt; over email (since email is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/can-email-ever-be-secure/&#34;&gt;not that secure anyways&lt;/a&gt;, even when encrypted), so the fact that it is less security-focused was okay for my use case (I&amp;rsquo;m not up against any state-level adversaries as far as I know). It would allow me to keep my email at my personal domain, use whatever email client I like best, and give me a catch-all address all while saving some money. My next step was to do the migration, which I&amp;rsquo;ll cover next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-migration&#34;&gt;The Migration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was already using my own domain, the biggest hurdle with changing email providers (informing everyone of your new address) was already handled. All that remained for me to do was to reconfigure my DNS records to direct traffic to my new provider, and migrate my email archive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reconfiguring my DNS was relatively simple. The first step was to setup my addresses on Mailbox.org, so that when the emails started flowing they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get bounced. The process for doing so is outlined in their &lt;a href=&#34;https://kb.mailbox.org/display/MBOKBEN/What+is+an+alias+and+how+do+I+use+it&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;I created an alias for the address I do most of my sending from (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jordan@jordancrane.me&#34;&gt;jordan@jordancrane.me&lt;/a&gt;), and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://kb.mailbox.org/display/MBOKBEN/Using+catch-all+alias+with+own+domain&#34;&gt;catch-all&lt;/a&gt; to handle the inbound aliases that I had configured in ProtonMail (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:web@jordancrane.me&#34;&gt;web@jordancrane.me&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:work@jordancrane.me&#34;&gt;work@jordancrane.me&lt;/a&gt;). Next, I reconfigured my MX record with the Mailbox.org values, and did the same for the SPF and DKIM TXT records, all of which is detailed &lt;a href=&#34;https://kb.mailbox.org/display/MBOKBEN/Using+e-mail+addresses+of+your+domain&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Small item of note: the Mailbox.org DKIM records differ from those of ProtonMail, and are significantly more lengthy&amp;mdash;if you&amp;rsquo;re using AWS Route 53 for your DNS, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to split the records with quotations, but no line breaks as described &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/premiumsupport/knowledge-center/route53-resolve-dkim-text-record-error/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. After using &lt;code&gt;dig&lt;/code&gt; and a few test emails to verify that everything had worked I removed all my ProtonMail records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To migrate my archived emails, first I setup my new Mailbox.org email address in Mail.app on my Mac (you can use Thunderbird or any other mail client, I&amp;rsquo;m just a default kind of guy). I then used the ProtonMail &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonmail.com/import-export&#34;&gt;Import-Export Tool&lt;/a&gt; to export all my emails into .mbox files on my computer. Once that completed, I imported the &lt;code&gt;Archive.mbox&lt;/code&gt; file into my email client locally, and simply dragged all the emails from that folder into my Mailbox.org Archive folder. Syncing took a while (I had ~5,000 emails in my archive), but eventually it completed, and that was that. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a paid ProtonMail account (and thus don&amp;rsquo;t have access to the Import-Export tool) you can also do this by just dragging the emails from your existing Archive folder to the new folder in your email client. I ran into some issues with this since my email client became confused by the fact that I had 2 email accounts with the same address. If you are taking this approach I would suggest exporting the Archive folder for your existing email before setting up your new email in your client of choice (in Mail.app you can do this by right-clicking on the folder you wish to export). Then remove your existing email address from your client before adding your new address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it! I put this task off for a while because I thought it would be a giant pain, but in the end it was only a little bit of a pain. Now I live in a blissful world in which I can import .ics files into my calendar directly from my mobile email client.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>How My Three-Year Car Ownership Hiatus Came To An End</title>
        <link>https://blog.jordancrane.me/posts/2020/07/zipcar-to-car-ownership/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 12:26:07 -0700</pubDate>
        <author>Jordan Crane</author>
        <guid>https://blog.jordancrane.me/posts/2020/07/zipcar-to-car-ownership/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Back when I was in college I owned a 1995 manual-transmission SUV that was a total tank. It served me well during countless trips between Corvallis and Seattle, where my family lives, and on many adventures in between. It guzzled gas, was littered with CDs (the only method by which to listen to music without advertisements on the outdated stereo unit), and had stains on the cloth seats from where my parents&#39; dog had vomited all over it on the way to the vet; but man did I love that car. However, after graduation I moved to Portland and its utility waned. Parking in my downtown apartment building was more money than I was willing to pay, and I either took transit or biked everywhere. As a temporary fix I left it in the parking lot at work until they told me to either move it or expect it to be impounded (it lasted a surprising 4 months there before someone noticed). At that point, I decided the old beast had become more of a burden than a benefit, so I sold it and signed up for a car2go membership. Thus began my car-free existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This existence went on for several happy years. I left my job at an office in the suburbs for one that was based in the heart of downtown, and biked to work religiously, rain or shine. I built a bike trailer for hauling groceries. I rented vehicles for road trips, trucks for moving, and fostered an anti-car sentiment in my heart. However, late last year I received a dark omen: car2go, by then re-branded as ShareNow, was ceasing operations in Portland. No longer could I walk a few blocks and pick up a car on a whim if I wanted to go on a hike or buy something on Craigslist. While this was a major blow to my low-car lifestyle, I attempted to stick it out for a while longer. Day trips became more infrequent, since renting a car from a rental agency for a single day just wasn&amp;rsquo;t cost effective. My sphere of recreational spaces shrunk significantly. I was still against owning a car, since not owning one had become part of my identity, but the seed of internal conflict had been planted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the coronavirus pandemic struck. All of a sudden, public transit was a much less viable option, ridesharing seemed risky, and all modes of getting out of town that didn&amp;rsquo;t involve driving oneself became relatively infeasible. In the midst of this, my partner and I rented a car to go camping for a weekend and I had the thought:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would sure be nice if I could do this more often; with more spontaneity and fewer logistics. Maybe I should buy a car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the idea of giving money to the automotive industry with its misleading advertising and government lobbyists repelled me, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but think of the things I&amp;rsquo;d missed out on by not owning a car: the rendezvouses with friends that I missed since I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get a ride; the trips that I didn&amp;rsquo;t take due to the mental barrier of spending money on a rental car instead of those costs being hidden in the cost of ownership. I began looking at cars online, and soon fell victim to that common consumer tendency of wanting something I didn&amp;rsquo;t have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally I thought I had decided what I wanted and called a dealership to find out how much a car was, thinking I would finally bite the bullet, but at the last moment I did the math and realized how big of a monthly expense a car would be. I drew back again, second guessing the thought process that had brought me to the brink. I thought about how much time I could rent a car for each month for that monthly figure, which didn&amp;rsquo;t even include maintenance or gas. I also worried that owning a car would change the way that I lived, encouraging me to drive when I could otherwise bike, walk, or take transit. I resolved to give my ideal of living without a car one last breath, and signed up for Zipcar; the last remaining car-share outfit in town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Zipcar use had a bumpy start. My partner and I wanted to go pick peaches on a farm outside of town, so I sought out a car close to me. I found that the nearest Zipcar station to my (very central) neighborhood was a 40-minute walk. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t bike since I was picking up a car without a bike rack, so I took a Lyft across the river to fetch the car. When I got to the Zipcar station, I found it was in a covered parking garage, so the Zipcar didn&amp;rsquo;t have cell reception and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t unlock. I spent 10 minutes trying to unlock the car, and kept receiving &amp;ldquo;Something went wrong&amp;rdquo; errors in the app. I called support, was on hold for 30 minutes, and once on the phone with them they asked me to try to unlock the vehicle again. Through some miracle in the reflections of the cellular signals and dumb luck, this time the car unlocked. I asked support to refund me for the 30 minutes of my reservation I spent trying to unlock the car, and they told me they couldn&amp;rsquo;t, since the car was now unlocked. I pressed and they instead said they would extend my reservation by 30 minutes free of charge (later on the receipt it was shown that this extension was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; free of charge, but actually charged at the normal rate). At this point I should have abandoned my plan and just counted my $50 as a loss, and found something else to do for the day, but I was in the car and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to disappoint my partner, so I forged on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drive out to the farm was uneventful, and the car was clean and pleasant. We pulled up to the farm and stashed our things in the car. I glanced at my cell phone and saw I had 2 bars of service and LTE, which was somewhat worrisome, but against my better judgment I assumed that if the lock signal could get through from my phone to the car, the unlock signal could make it too. I crossed my fingers and locked the car. Picking peaches was wonderful: it was a beautiful, northwest summer day, and the whole farm smelled of ripe peaches. We picked a whole box, paid for them, and then made our way back to the car, hopeful that we could hit another farm on the way home to pick blueberries as well. I pulled out my phone, held my breath, and pressed the unlock button. I then saw those three words I had dreaded:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something went wrong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart sank. I called support and was greeted with a cheerful voice that informed me they were experiencing higher-than-normal call volume, and placed me on hold. Little did I know how familiar I would become with their hold music by the end of the day. It seemed like it could have been the backing track of some low-key indie rock tune, the chord progression was slightly more complex than a I-IV-V, and had a bit of pizzazz thrown in, some sort of seventh chord that built a bit of suspense before it looped back to the start. I listened to the tune for 20 minutes, and was finally connected to a support representative, who after much silent typing informed me that they would need to send roadside assistance out to help us. He assured me that roadside assistance would call me within the next 30 minutes to get everything worked out, and hung up. My partner decided to go pick some more fruit at the farm, and I plopped myself down in a shady spot to await the call. I explained to the man directing parking for the farm what was going on, and he assured me that we could take as much time as needed to work things out. He told me that his wife owned the farm, and that he would inform her of what was going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 minutes went by, and I had not heard anything from roadside assistance. My partner had returned from the orchard again, and had joined me in the shade. It was getting close to 100°F, and we had locked our water in the car, so she had bought a soda at the farm&amp;rsquo;s store (they were out of stock on water). We both gulped some down to ward of dehydration. I decided it was time to call support again, and as expected, was greeted with the same automated statement about call volume and hold music. This time I was on hold for 30 minutes, at which point the music stopped, and my call was dropped. Apparently Zipcar&amp;rsquo;s hold system wasn&amp;rsquo;t designed to handle the current volume either. I called again, and after another 30 minutes was connected with a representative. I explained the situation and he apologized profusely, promising to transfer me directly to roadside assistance, at which point I was put on hold again. Another 20 minutes elapsed. The phone was picked up again, not by roadside assistance, but by the same representative. He told me that we &amp;ldquo;could abandon the vehicle&amp;rdquo;, and they would handle the rest. I explained to him that our belongings were still in the car, and after a long pause he said that in that case, roadside assistance would call us within the next hour to &lt;em&gt;tell us the ETA of the tow truck&lt;/em&gt;. On top of that, after it arrived we would still need to get our own ride home, from a location that ridesharing and transit didn&amp;rsquo;t service, where I had unsurprisingly used Zipcar to get to since &lt;em&gt;it was my only option for transportation&lt;/em&gt;. I gave a half-hearted thank you and hung up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point we decided to take matters into our own hands. I called a locksmith, who politely informed me he could be at our location in 45 minutes. He arrived on the dot, opened the car for us, charged me $95, and went to help his next customer. Even with the car unlocked, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t start since our reservation had expired with no way to extend it due to the car not having an internet connection. With our possessions in hand, I called a close friend who was thankfully unoccupied and willing to drive an hour round trip to save us from purgatory. While we were waiting for him to arrive the owner of the farm came down to check on us, expressed surprise that we were still there, and very graciously offered us some bottled water. It was ice cold and was the best thing I had tasted all day. By the time my friend had arrived, it had been one-and-a-half hours since my last support call had ended, and I still hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard anything about the tow truck&amp;rsquo;s ETA. I told the owner of the farm we were sorry for ditching the car on her land, and that if Zipcar didn&amp;rsquo;t show up to get it she could do what she needed to have it removed. With that, we were finally homeward bound, after five grueling hours in a situation we had zero control over. Finally at 7PM (seven hours after my initial call to support), I received a text informing me the the tow truck would arrive in &lt;em&gt;two hours&lt;/em&gt;. That is, if we had waited for Zipcar to resolve the situation, we would have been sitting around waiting for nine hours total. The tow truck driver called at 9:45PM, asking us how to get the car back into the parking garage, since his tow truck wouldn&amp;rsquo;t fit into the garage. I told him I didn&amp;rsquo;t know, and expressed my sympathy. I&amp;rsquo;m sure he spent 30 minutes on hold with Zipcar trying to figure it out, assuming he decided against just impounding the car instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience shook my confidence in Zipcar as a service. I never had these issues with car2go, since they gave you the actual keys to unlock the car, which I understand is probably much more expensive to replace in the case of a loss than a key-card, but also gives me much more confidence that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be stranded in a much worse situation (outside of cell reception, for example). I should note that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t received my &amp;ldquo;Zipcard&amp;rdquo; at this point, since I had just signed up for the service, but even so the same situation could have occurred with the card in hand had we overshot our reservation time. On top of that their customer service was so atrocious, with no regard for the situation that the customer was in, that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t fathom needing to deal with them again should anything else ever go wrong. Their seemingly default solution of &amp;ldquo;find your own way home&amp;rdquo; is frankly unacceptable for a company who&amp;rsquo;s primary service is providing a way to get to places you couldn&amp;rsquo;t get to otherwise. I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the process of attempting to be reimbursed for the locksmith and the four hours of my reservation that I spent locked out of the car, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have high hopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this was the final nail in the coffin. Though I&amp;rsquo;m loathe to admit it, the very next day I went out and purchased a lightly used car with a 75% down payment that I&amp;rsquo;d been saving up and a small loan that I plan to pay off as soon as possible. I was planning to wait to buy in cash, but after this experience I never wanted to use a Zipcar again if I could help it, and I wanted to be able to go do things outside during the summer in the midst of lockdown. Thus ended my hiatus from car ownership. I won&amp;rsquo;t blame it all on Zipcar, as it was a slow trek to the realization that America is just not well-suited to a car-free or low-car lifestyle if you like to leave the city on occasion, but the frustration and helplessness of being stranded definitely pushed me over the edge. Maybe someday car2go or something like it will return to Portland, and I can sell my car again. Until then I&amp;rsquo;ll just have to exercise my willpower to only use my new mode of mobility when I really need to, and not when it&amp;rsquo;s just rainy out and I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to bike a few miles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>2020-07-19T18:10:21-07:00</title>
        <link>https://blog.jordancrane.me/microposts/2020/07/20/181020/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 18:10:21 -0700</pubDate>
        <author>Jordan Crane</author>
        <guid>https://blog.jordancrane.me/microposts/2020/07/20/181020/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Giving microposts a try, seems like it could encourage me to post more often and make up for my Twitter deficiency&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Better Than Zoom: Serendipity Over Video</title>
        <link>https://blog.jordancrane.me/posts/2020/07/better-than-zoom/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 20:44:28 -0700</pubDate>
        <author>Jordan Crane</author>
        <guid>https://blog.jordancrane.me/posts/2020/07/better-than-zoom/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I&amp;rsquo;m currently unemployed thanks to the global pandemic, the transition to remote work in my previous position brought about many changes to the way my team and I worked; some good, some bad. While I enjoyed the ability to work uninterrupted during periods of flow, I missed the spontaneous exchanges that were prone to happen in an office space but failed to materialize in the remote world. This was somewhat mitigated by the fact that my teammates and I were already close, but it still felt hindered. In the process of searching for new employment, I&amp;rsquo;ve been attracted to remote positions due to their perks, but I&amp;rsquo;ve also found my mind being drawn to thoughts of how it might be more difficult to form those initial relationships in a fully remote environment. Today I want to explore how a company might foster serendipitous encounters in a remote workspace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-we-tried&#34;&gt;Things We Tried&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My team at Acorns explored a few different ways to maintain our culture of collaboration given the tools we had at our disposal; namely Google Meet and Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;watercooler-channel&#34;&gt;Watercooler Channel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing we tried was having a private team watercooler channel for casual discussion. This was helpful in replicating the feeling of spinning your chair around to talk to one another about what we did over the weekend and other non-work-related things. However, it was unable to fully capture the feeling of doing so, since text chat lacks the feeling of personal connection that an actual conversation creates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;video-call-activities&#34;&gt;Video Call Activities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another tool we used was engaging in social activities over video call. Our team particularly liked playing Smash Bros together, so we would often hop on a call and play a few rounds together at the end of the day. This was great for maintaining a feeling of camaraderie, and providing a venue for informal discussion about the events of the day, but obviously lacked the spontaneity of sitting down at the same table for lunch, for example. Our office as a whole also tried a few virtual happy hours, and while these were enjoyable, the problem with gatherings larger than 3-5 people on a video call is the feeling of passing a talking stick around a circle. When someone is speaking they inherently become the center of attention, and this often hinders the natural flow of conversation since side conversations can&amp;rsquo;t split off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;persistent-video-hangout&#34;&gt;Persistent Video Hangout&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last technique we used was to have a persistent video chat available to hop in and out of at will. This allowed Slack conversations to organically evolve into real-time conversations as the complexity increased, and also provided a venue for the team to be in a virtual space without an express purpose. That last idea is an important one, since most video calls have a set topic, and once you&amp;rsquo;re done talking about it the call is over. This, however, also had downsides. Being in the persistent chat meant that you got distracted more often, and as soon as two people were having a conversation in the hangout it was no longer a viable space to hang around in for the rest of the team. The latter issue harks back to the fact that side conversations aren&amp;rsquo;t possible in current video call solutions, so everyone in the call always has to be onboard with what is happening in the call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-we-do-better&#34;&gt;How Can We Do Better?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept being pursued in all of the attempts in the previous section is that of a virtual space to supplant the physical space provided by an office. The space acts as a medium to facilitate collaboration and camaraderie, since the space allows individuals to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See when someone is available for collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encounter people they don&amp;rsquo;t work with directly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have conversations about non-work-related topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be together even when they are working alone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the question is how can current collaboration tools be modified to provide such a space. It can be broken down into lists of desirable and undesirable features/traits of the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;desirable&#34;&gt;Desirable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitates turning asynchronous conversations into real-time conversations when it becomes apparent that pairing or explaining something on a call would be more effective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows side conversations to spin off organically while maintaining the feeling of being in the same space (creating a separate call doesn&amp;rsquo;t achieve this well, since swapping between the side conversation and the hub conversation doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel cohesive)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shows when someone is open to a conversation or looking to not be distracted (virtual equivalent of headphones on/headphones off)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows for serendipitous encounters to occur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;undesirable&#34;&gt;Undesirable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space becomes hard to use when a side conversation is happening, or when there are more than a small number of people in the space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inhabitants of the space get distracted when they want to be focused&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space creates a sense of &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m here so we need to be talking about something&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;potential-solutions&#34;&gt;Potential Solutions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thought that continually came to me as I was in virtual happy hours or persistent hangouts was that of being able to move closer or further away from other inhabitants of the space we were using, depending on who I was trying to have a conversation with, or what I was trying to get out of the space. At a real happy hour you can swap seats if you are interested in a conversation on the other end of the table, or lean to the left or right to join different threads of discussion. In a real office you can wheel your chair over to your coworker&amp;rsquo;s desk to pair on a problem, or to talk about a movie you saw recently. It seems to me that replicating this ability in a virtual space is key to making it feel more like a physical space. This spawned two distinct possibilities in my mind for solutions, either a proximity-based video chat service that allows you move between conversations, or a system consisting of a lobby and rooms that allows an inhabitant to see who is in each &amp;ldquo;room&amp;rdquo; (like seeing who is sitting at each table in a break room). Another nice feature would be the ability to &amp;ldquo;overhear&amp;rdquo; conversations happening in an adjacent &amp;ldquo;room&amp;rdquo;, or somewhere nearby in the proximity-based solution. The proximity-based solution, while harder to implement, would be the most similar to a physical space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was in the midst of considering these possibilities I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://gather.town&#34;&gt;Gather&lt;/a&gt;, which seems to be the only product that is breaking the mold of traditional video calls in this way. Gather allows you to create an 8-bit virtual space, which inhabitants can move their avatars around like a video game. As you get close to another inhabitant&amp;rsquo;s avatar, a video call is created between the two of you. It&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate that I was already without a job by the time I came across the site, since as soon as I saw it I was excited by the possibilities that it could enable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Gather or a similar product, a team could create a virtual office, which contains virtual desks, virtual meeting rooms, and virtual common areas. Inhabitants could be at their desk while they are working alone, but also walk over to the virtual desk of a coworker, or run into someone in the hallway on the way to a virtual meeting room. If a conversation was happening in a common area, others could drop in or side conversations could split off organically, as they do in the real world. Such a setup could provide many of the benefits of working in an office, without sacrificing the benefits of remote work. My main concern with such a solution is the problem of surveillance, it could easily become another way to keep tabs on workers and penalize them for not being in the virtual office on time. However, it would still be a very interesting technology to experiment with in a time when so many companies are undergoing jarring transitions to a fully-distributed workforce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting to the end of this post I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% sure that I had a concrete point to make, other than that Slack and Zoom (and their contemporaries) don&amp;rsquo;t have to be the be-all and end-all of remote work. There are still ways to push the boundaries and experiment with other modes of remote collaboration. I hope this inspires you to continue searching for ways to foster better ways of working with your remote teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Hosting a GitHub User Site with Project Subdomains</title>
        <link>https://blog.jordancrane.me/posts/2020/06/github-pages-user-site-project-subdomains/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 19:15:15 -0700</pubDate>
        <author>Jordan Crane</author>
        <guid>https://blog.jordancrane.me/posts/2020/06/github-pages-user-site-project-subdomains/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started this site with the original purpose of hosting my resume for easy sharing without much else in mind. That&amp;rsquo;s still mostly all it does, but I&amp;rsquo;ve solved a few problems along the way to make deployments (slightly) cleaner, so I thought I would document my process here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep my resume in version control in a markdown file, and then use the fabulous &lt;a href=&#34;https://pandoc.org/&#34;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt; to convert it to a variety of formats, namely an HTML file for hosting and a PDF file for sharing over email. The code can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jordancrane/pandoc_resume&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, which is forked from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mszep/pandoc_resume&#34;&gt;The Markdown Resume&lt;/a&gt;, which is based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.chmd.fr/editing-a-cv-in-markdown-with-pandoc.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; blog post. So suffice it to say this is not my idea, but I love the approach and have tweaked it along the way to meet my needs. In order to get the generated files from my resume repository into my GitHub Pages &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jordancrane/site&#34;&gt;site repository&lt;/a&gt;, I was originally using a submodule and simply generating the resume files as part of the deployment process. This had a few drawbacks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every time I changed my resume I had to redeploy the whole site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use &lt;code&gt;docker-compose&lt;/code&gt; to build the resume, and Docker was attempting to use the same container to build it in the resume repository and in the site submodule. This meant I had to run &lt;code&gt;docker container rm&lt;/code&gt; every time I switched between updating the resume and deploying the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to mitigate these issues I decided to host the resume independently as its own GitHub pages project site, and simply link to it from this site. I could have just used the built-in GitHub Pages setup of the project site being a path under my user site, but I liked the idea of making it a subdomain more (&lt;code&gt;resume.jordancrane.me&lt;/code&gt; just looks more appealing than &lt;code&gt;jordancrane.me/pandoc_resume/&lt;/code&gt; to me, and I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for details that literally no one else will notice). To deploy the generated files from my resume repository I opted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/cobyism/4730490&#34;&gt;use a subtree&lt;/a&gt; due to the simplicity. This isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;ideal&lt;/em&gt; so I may revisit it in the future, but it works for now. Assuming that you already have your personal site configured with a custom domain (GitHub&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/github/working-with-github-pages/managing-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; on this is pretty good) adding a subdomain is pretty straightforward. All you need to do is configure a &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; file in the root of your deployment branch with your desired subdomain, mine looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;resume.jordancrane.me
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then you simply configure that as your project&amp;rsquo;s custom domain under the repository settings, and add a new CNAME record to your DNS provider that directs the subdomain host (&lt;code&gt;resume&lt;/code&gt;) to your GitHub Pages domain (&lt;code&gt;jordancrane.github.io.&lt;/code&gt;). This is pretty simple, and GitHub also documents this well, but I was initially confused by the fact that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to point directly to the project site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve configured this, I can deploy my resume individually directly from it&amp;rsquo;s repository, without deploying the entire site. Additionally I was able to remove the &lt;code&gt;docker-compose&lt;/code&gt; step from the build process for the site, so I no longer have to deal with container conflicts from building it in multiple places. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are better ways still to do this, but I&amp;rsquo;d be lying if I said the small quality of life improvements brought by this change don&amp;rsquo;t bring me some joy. My next step is to move my deployment processes into GitHub Actions so I can get rid of my bad deploy scripts, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>My Super Special Terminal Setup</title>
        <link>https://blog.jordancrane.me/posts/2020/06/my-terminal-setup/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 20:00:25 -0700</pubDate>
        <author>Jordan Crane</author>
        <guid>https://blog.jordancrane.me/posts/2020/06/my-terminal-setup/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me you are super particular about your terminal setup. I am capable of working in most terminal environments, but since I spend a lot more time using the setup on my personal computer than those on machines I SSH into, I figure it&amp;rsquo;s worth spoiling myself in that context, despite the fact that it might incur a slight efficiency penalty when I&amp;rsquo;m using machines without all the niceties that I like to add. Since I am now in the process of setting up my development environment once again, I figured I would take this opportunity to document all the things I do in a post so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to go through so much trial and error every time to remember how I like things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;terminal&#34;&gt;Terminal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first, don&amp;rsquo;t even open Terminal. Get &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iterm2.com&#34;&gt;iTerm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;package-manager&#34;&gt;Package Manager&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing you&amp;rsquo;ll need is a package manager. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt;, but I found it to be confusing as someone who&amp;rsquo;s spent time with other package managers like &lt;code&gt;apt&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pacman&lt;/code&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve also run into issues when macOS updates are installed; sometimes the permissions of your &lt;code&gt;/usr/local&lt;/code&gt; directory get reset, and consequently your whole environment gets screwed up. The latter experience left me with a sour taste in my mouth and a compulsive desire to Dockerize everything, so now I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macports.org&#34;&gt;MacPorts&lt;/a&gt;. I found &lt;a href=&#34;https://saagarjha.com/blog/2019/04/26/thoughts-on-macos-package-managers/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; to be a well thought out comparison between the two, if you&amp;rsquo;re interested something more nuanced than my knee-jerk reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;docker&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not strictly a terminal thing, but something that&amp;rsquo;s important to my environment, due to the aforementioned compulsive Dockerization habit. I just install the &lt;a href=&#34;https://hub.docker.com/editions/community/docker-ce-desktop-mac/&#34;&gt;Docker For Mac&lt;/a&gt; app, not sure if that&amp;rsquo;s the best way to do it but it&amp;rsquo;s worked well for me so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;Shell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve got iTerm and MacPorts setup, time to install your shell of choice (unless it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;bash&lt;/code&gt;, which is fine I guess). Personally I&amp;rsquo;ve always been partial to &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt;, mostly because it&amp;rsquo;s what all my friends used in college (a nuanced decision making process, I know). Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been considering checking out &lt;code&gt;fish&lt;/code&gt;, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to it yet. To install &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt;, just run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo port install zsh zsh-completions
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;A necessary companion to &lt;code&gt;zsh&lt;/code&gt; in my mind is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sorin-ionescu/prezto&#34;&gt;Prezto&lt;/a&gt;, which adds a ton of nice features like history substring search, mostly reasonable &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; aliases, and &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt; bindings for your prompt, among other things. It&amp;rsquo;s recommended that you fork the repo so you can store your personal configuration in GitHub. My fork is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jordancrane/prezto&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;; it&amp;rsquo;s pretty basic, just turning on a few colorization settings, adding some extra aliases, and tweaking my favorite prompt theme to have emoji (the most important change obviously).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve typically used a modified version of the &lt;code&gt;steeef&lt;/code&gt; prompt that comes with Prezto, but with this install I also discovered &lt;a href=&#34;https://starship.rs&#34;&gt;starship&lt;/a&gt;, which seems interesting. I&amp;rsquo;m unsure how much feature overlap it has with Prezto, so whether I continue using it or not remains yet to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;text-editor&#34;&gt;Text Editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I&amp;rsquo;m concerned Vim is the One True Text Editor, and I mostly refuse to use any application that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a Vim bindings plugin. However, having gone way down the rabbit hole of Vim tweaking in the past, I will say that overall I prefer to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://neovim.io&#34;&gt;NeoVim&lt;/a&gt; since it tends to be easier to get plugins to work well with NeoVim without recompiling with a bunch of different variant flags. Install it with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo port install neovim
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;and add&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;alias vim=&#39;nvim&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;to your &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; for an easy transition. Two bindings I find important are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;nnoremap j gj
nnoremap k gk
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;which allow you to move up and down wrapped lines (helpful for writing blog posts and whatnot without needing to add line breaks manually).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;font&#34;&gt;Font&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy &lt;a href=&#34;https://pcaro.es/p/hermit/&#34;&gt;Hermit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;colorscheme&#34;&gt;Colorscheme&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the Apprentice color scheme for both &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/romainl/Apprentice&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/romainl/apprentice-colorschemes&#34;&gt;iTerm&lt;/a&gt;. Do note that the background color for iTerm in that repo is a little off from that in the Vim one, change it to &lt;code&gt;#262626&lt;/code&gt; to avoid having a frame around your Vim window. For installing it to Vim, I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/junegunn/vim-plug&#34;&gt;vim-plug&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that&amp;rsquo;s about everything&amp;hellip; This will likely be a living document that I will modify as my preferences change.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
